icici lombard health insurance
icici lombard general insurance company
is one of the leading health insurers in
india
that protects you from sudden financial
burden it is a joint
venture of icici bank limited from india
and fairfax financial holdings limited
from canada
it provides top service along with a
good number of network hospitals
and claims support let us now take a
look at the key features
of the plans number one
network hospital lombard has a tie up
with its network hospitals for offering
cashless hospitalization
to the insured person where you don't
have to pay a single penny to the
hospital directly
with the cashless facility all the
medical expenses
are borne by icici lombard
lombard is empaneled with 6 500 plus
network
hospitals across india
which offers complementary health
checkup pre
and post hospitalization expenses
coverage for pre-existing diseases etc
number two solvency ratio
irdi has made it mandatory to maintain a
health solvency ratio
of 1.5 for every insurance
company lombard has a solvency ratio
of 2.2 that very well suits the criteria
suggested by irdi and indicates the
company's highest
claim-paying ability number three
claim support which is the assessment of
the claim
settling ability of an insurer
in irdi annual report 2019-2020
the company's claim support within three
months is 96.93
that means out of 100 claims icici
lombard has
settled 96 of claims in three months
lombard is among the top three insurers
in india
number four market share market share
determines the business volume
and it also measures the consumer's
preference for a product
over other similar products business
volume refers to the total number of
policies
that are sold by an insurance company
and the premiums collected
as per irdi annual report 2018 to 2019
the annual gross premium was 2267.16
crore
and as per irdi annual report 2019 to
the company's annual gross premium has
risen to
2695.15 crores
which shows a significant growth
benefits of icicle ombarg health
insurance
number one pre and post hospitalization
number two coverage for pre-existing
diseases
number three tax benefit which can be
availed on premium paid
under section 80d of the income tax act
1961. number four
ambulance charges number five
24 7 customer service
let us take a look at the different
types of plans offered by
lombard health insurance number one
health booster plan which is a super
top-up plan
[Music]
it covers an individual's extra medical
bills when your existing health plan
does not cover it
second is lombard complete health
insurance
which is a family health insurance plan
again we have family health insurance
plans which are
arrogance and given a policy and
healthcare plus
next is against accidental death and
disability
which is personal protect plan
next corona coverage plan against kovite
what is not covered under icici lombard
health insurance
cosmetic surgery intentional destruction
of property
suicidal death claim any kind of loss or
damage to the property because of war
or world-like situation any injury
occurred within the 15 days of the
policy commencement
any injury occurred under the influence
of alcohol
natural wear and tear of the property of
the policy holder
now let us talk about the most
significant aspect
icici lombard health insurance claim
process
inform the company about the unforeseen
event within 48 hours
submit the required documents instructed
by the customer care
officer in order to proceed with the
claim process
download the claim application form from
the website
or you can get it from the nearest
branch office
submit all the required documents along
with icici lombard
health insurance claim form to the
respective branch
the cashless claims are processed in a
set period of time
and the reimbursement claims are settled
within 30 days
from the date the claim has been made
do not forget to check out the documents
required
which are a duly filled application form
original bills discharge papers
receipt related to the hospitalization
medical bills of chemist along with a
valid prescription
all the copies of medical examination
report
thank you for hearing out to us that was
all about
icici lombard health insurance
do let us know in the comment section if
you have any queries
and also let us know if you want us to
make a video on any suggested particular
topic
thank you for your time stay tuned with
policyex.com